Drop everything. Save the world.
Big Hero 6 is a adventure, family, animation film directed by Chris Williams.
A special bond develops between plus-sized inflatable robot Baymax, and prodigy Hiro
Hamada, who team up with a group of friends to form a band of high-tech heroes.
Baymax (voice), played by Scott Adsit.
Hiro Hamada (voice), played by Ryan Potter.
Tadashi Hamada (voice), played by Daniel Henney.
Fred (voice), played by T.J. Miller.
GoGo Tomago (voice), played by Jamie Chung.
Wasabi (voice), played by Damon Wayans Jr..
Big Hero 6 is a 2014 American animated superhero film loosely
based on the superhero team from Marvel Comics.
Produced by Walt Disney Animation Studios, it was directed by Don Hall and
Chris Williams, and written by Jordan Roberts, Robert L.
Baird and Daniel Gerson.
It stars the voices of Scott Adsit, Ryan Potter, Daniel Henney, T.J.
Miller, Jamie Chung, Damon Wayans Jr., Genesis Rodriguez,
James Cromwell, Maya Rudolph and Alan Tudyk.
The film tells the story of Hiro Hamada, a young robotics prodigy and Baymax, a
healthcare robot invented by his late older brother, Tadashi.
They form a superhero team to combat a masked
supervillain responsible for Tadashi's death.
Big Hero 6 is the first Disney animated film to feature Marvel Comics
characters, whose parent company was acquired by Disney in 2009.
Walt Disney Animation Studios created new software
technology to produce the animation.
Big Hero 6 debuted at the 27th Tokyo International Film Festival on October
23, 2014 and was released in the United States on November 7.
The film received positive reviews from critics, and grossed $658
million, becoming the highest-grossing animated film of 2014.
At the 87th Academy Awards, the film won Best Animated Feature.
It also received seven nominations for Annie Awards,
winning one, and a Golden Globe nomination.
Big Hero 6 was followed by three television series: Big Hero 6: The Series
premiered in 2017, Baymax Dreams premiered in 2018, and Baymax!
premiered in 2022.
The film explores themes of friendship, martial arts, hero,
sibling relationship, san francisco, california.
The tone is lighthearted and uplifting.